Guide to the David Peck Todd Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, PRE-1922 (1878-1922); Series I; 5 linear feet (13 boxes)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Letters addressed to David Peck Todd and Mabel Loomis Todd jointly by Millicent Todd
      See: box 12, folder 391 See: box 11, folder 367
    - Bingham, Millicent Todd:
      - (50), 1885 - 1902 (Box 11, Folder 367)
      - (47), 1903 - 1916, n.y. (Box 11, Folder 368)
      - (11), 1917 - 1922 (Box 11, Folder 369)
    - Bingham, Walter van Dyck [son-in law], (3), 1921 - 1922 (Box 11, Folder 370)
    - Bower, E.L. (DPT's Cousin), (1), 1921 February 21 (Box 11, Folder 371)
    - Brown, S.P. [relative of DPT?], (2), 1860 (Box 11, Folder 372)
    - Capwell, Julia A (MLT relative), (1), 1894 February 21 (Box 11, Folder 373)
    - Compton, Naomi Todd (sister), (12), 1877 - 1894 (Box 11, Folder 374)
    - Gardner, E.C. (MLT relative: 1st cousin of EJL), (2), [ca. 1911], 1914 January 14 (Box 11, Folder 375)
    - Gresham, Fannie Todd (niece, daughter of SET, Jr.), (1), [1916] December 16 (Box 11, Folder 376)
    - Ingersoll, Edward P. (DPT's great uncle on father's side), (1), 1886 November 23 (Box 11, Folder 377)
    - Ingersoll, Edward P., Jr. (DPT's father's cousin), (2), 1879 March 3, 1888 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 378)
    - Ingersoll, Lucy M (DPT's father's cousin), (1), 1879 May 26 (Box 11, Folder 379)
    - Kent, Everett (MLT relative, Wilder side), (4), post-1922 (Box 11, Folder 380)
    - Loomis, Eben Jenks (father-in-law), (7), 1880 - 1908 (Box 11, Folder 381)
    - Loomis, Eben Jenks, letters from David Peck Todd:
      - (36), 1878 - 1888 (Box 11, Folder 382)
      - (33), 1889 - 1907 (Box 11, Folder 383)
    - Loomis, M.A.W. (DPT's mother-in-law), (19), 1879 - 1907; undated (Box 11, Folder 384)
    - Mason, William A. (MLT relative - grandson of MWF Wilder's sister), (1), 1911 November 26 (Box 11, Folder 385)
    - Peck, David and Huldah [David Peck, uncle of DPT] (1) (Box 11, Folder 386)
    - Sheip, Ella Bower (DPT's cousin), (3), 1908 January 15, 24 [1908] (Box 11, Folder 387)
    - Shenklin, John Gilbert (MLT relative: husband of Gertrude Avery, the daughter of Susan Look Avery), (1), 1894 April 1 (Box 11, Folder 388)
    - Smith, C. E. (cousin on DPT's father's side), (1), [ca. 1922] (Box 11, Folder 389)
    - Todd, Cornelia A. (cousin), (1), 1880 May 30 (Box 11, Folder 390)
    - Todd, David Peck letters to Eben Jenks Loomis
      See: box 11, folders 382 See: box 11, folders 383
    - Todd, Mabel Loomis:
      For Post-1922 correspondence, see also: box 12a, folder 411
      - (11 letters), 1878 June (Box 12, Folder 391)
      - (8 letters), 1878 July (Box 12, Folder 392)
      - (12 letters), 1878 August - October (Box 12, Folder 393)
      - (13 letters), 1879 - 1881 (Box 12, Folder 394)
      - (13 letters), 1882 (Box 12, Folder 395)
      - (12 letters), 1883 (Box 12, Folder 396)
      - (40 letters), 1884 - 1891 (Box 12, Folder 397)
      - (19 letters), 1890, 1891 (Box 12, Folder 398)
      - (31 letters), 1892 - 1894; n.y. (Box 12, Folder 399)
      - (31 letters), 1895 - 1897; n.y. (Box 12, Folder 400)
      - (41 letters), 1898 - 1900; undated (Box 12, Folder 401)
      - (32 letters), 1901 - 1904 (Box 12, Folder 402)
      - (57 letters), 1905 - 1908 (Box 12A, Folder 403)
      - (41 letters), 1909 - 1913 (Box 12A, Folder 404)
      - (3 letters), undated, before 1913 (Box 12A, Folder 405)
      - (6 letters), 1915 - 1922 (Box 12A, Folder 406)
    - Todd, Rhoda Peck (mother):
      - (3 letters), 1880, 1888, 1895 (Box 12A, Folder 407)
      - Bills and related correspondence, 1898-1901
        See: Box 107, folder 44
    - Todd, Millicent
      See: box 11, folder 367
    - Todd, Sereno E. (father), (2), 1877, 1882 (Box 12A, Folder 408)
    - Todd, Sereno E., Jr. (brother), (1), 1875 December 21 (Box 12A, Folder 409)
    - Tracy, William (son of Ella B. Sheip, cousin of DPT), (1), 1922 October 22 (Box 12A, Folder 410)
    - Tracy, William B. (post 1922) (son of DPT's cousin, Ella Sheip), (9), 1923 December 6 - 1924 November 18 (Box 12A, Folder 411)
    - Wilder, E.F. (DPT's mother-in-law's cousin), (2), 1903 May 2; 1912 March 13 (Box 12A, Folder 412)
    - Wilder, H.A. (MLT's relative on mother's side), (11), 1897, 1899, [ca. 1908], 1911, 1913, 1915, 1917 - 1918 (Box 12A, Folder 413)
    - Wilder, MWFJ (MLT's grandmother), (3), 1889, 1893 (Box 12A, Folder 414)
    - Wilder, Mary C. (cousin of MLT, later Keith), (1), [ca. 1903] (Box 12A, Folder 415)
- Scientific Subjects and Exhibitions, (1878-1939); Series II; 21.75 linear feet (54 boxes)
  A. General Astronomical notes
  These notes are arranged chronologically and cover the period 1878-1904. There is also a section arranged by subject, including manuscripts by others and collected by David P. Todd, clippings, and his own notes on astronomical topics.
  B. Mechanical and scientific ideas and inventions
  Included in this section are nonastronomical scientific ideas and inventions. These are arranged alphabetically and range from Aeroplanes to Vital Engineering. David P. Todd's ideas for telescopes and telescope mountings are included in this section.
  C. Astronomical Expeditions
  The expeditions are arranged by date beginning with Dallas in 1878 for observations of an eclipse of the sun and ending with the eclipse of 1932 in Maine. In addition to the scientific notes and photographs collected by David P. Todd, the expedition material generally includes photographs, notes by other members of the expedition, and memorabilia. The pattern used in arranging the expedition material is as follows:
  1. Legal-personal: passports, etc.
  2. Scientific and scholarly materials used in preparation, such as maps, charts, topographical studies
  3. David P. Todd scientific notes and observations
  4. Photos and sketches of astronomical phenomena
  5. Photographs of other aspects of the trip
  6. Report on the phenomena by David P. Todd
  7. Reports on the eclipse as viewed by others
  8. Newspaper reports of the expedition
  9. Newspaper reports of other views of the eclipse, other expeditions in the same area
  10. Manuscript memorabilia
  11. Financial memorabilia: expedition expenses, also Todd personal expenses
  12. Printed memorabilia: menus, letter paper from ships and hotels visited in transit, programs of entertainments, tickets, tradesmen's cards
  13. Examples of local newspapers collected as souvenirs
  14. Materials on the expedition locality collected later by the Todds
  D. Astronomical projects
  There are two archive boxes devoted to several astronomical projects which fall outside David P. Todd's main interest in eclipses. These subjects interested him intermittently throughout his life, and the files contain his notes, observations and clippings on the search for a trans-Neptunian planet, the observation of Saturn's rings, and signalling Mars. (In boxes 53 and 54.)
  - Literary quotations re: Astronomy (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Astronomical notes, Circa 1880's, 1878-1910, 1919-1923, undated (Box 13, Folder 2-8)
  - General Astronomical notebooks:
    - 1879, 1899, 1883-1884 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
    - 1900-1922, undated (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
  - Observations of Jupiter's Satellites, 1874-1881 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Occultations, 1874-1881 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Transits. notes, 1874 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    See also: box 104, folder 17
  - Equatorial; Occultation of Pleiades, 1875-1877 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - "Plan of Practical Search for Trans-Neptunian Planet,", 1877 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Notes re: Neptune and Uranus, 1875-1877
  - Discovery of Satellite to Mars by Asaph Hall: newspaper clippings, 1877 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Meridian Transits, 1877, 1880 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Sun spots, 1877-1887 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Trans-Neptunian Planet, 1877 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Transit of Mercury, 1878 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Computations of Uranus from Newcomb's Tables, [1878?] (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Simon Newcomb, New Tables of Eclipses, David P. Todd collaboration, 1879 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Comparison of Le Verrier's and Newcomb's Tables: Uranus and Neptune, [1880's?] (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Clock and star computations, 1881 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Transit of Mercury, 1881 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - American Ephemeris Proof journal and pages, 1882-1883 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Astronomical calculations daily [damaged], 1882, 1883 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Equatorial, 1882, 1883 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Annular Eclipse, 1883, 1885 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - American Ephemeris marked proofs, 1884 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Star Observations, 1885 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Sun Spot sketches, 1885 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Eclipse: notes, 16 March 1885 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Lunar Eclipse notes, photos, clippings, 22 July 1888 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Eclipse notes, clipping, 29 August 1886, 1889, 1896, 1897, 1903, 1925, undated (Box 16, Folder 37-38)
  - Lunar Eclipse notes, 1891 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Aurora Borealis, 23-30 April 1892 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous notes, clippings: eclipse 1893, Circa 1890's (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Lunar eclipse, 10 March 1895 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - notebook observations of Venus, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Annular eclipse, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Transit of Mercury, 1907 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Halley's Comet newspaper clippings by and about David P. Todd, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Observations of U Geminorum, 1911 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Eclipse, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Projected expedition to Egypt for observation of Mars and Saturn, 1913-1914 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Transit of Mercury, 6 November 1914 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Solar eclipse, 3 February 1916 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous notes, not scientific, to show state of mind, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Lunar eclipse clippings re: David P. Todd, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Corona without eclipse, Circa 1922 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Sun spots newspaper statements by David P. Todd, 1922, 1924, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Earthquake scare clippings quoting David P. Todd, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Transit of Mercury, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Totality tracks for various areas during 20th century, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Eclipse: proposals, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Mars, scrap notes, n. d. (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Spiral Nebulae, undated (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Astronomical phenomena drawings and illustrations (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Drawings of telescopes and other apparatus, 1897, 1902, 1903, 1905, undated (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - Recipients of publications, 1892, 1893, 1908-1910 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Memorabilia, printed astronomical forms; Naval Observatory, Washington, 1870's and 1880's (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - Memorabilia, printed, 1896-1914 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Pilot charts for eclipses, 1912, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Portraits of astronomers (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Baker, Robert H., B. A. 1904, Assistant to David P. Todd, Amherst writings of in Astronomical Journal, 1904, 1905, 1906 (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Schiaparelli, G."Rubra Canicula. A Study of Color Changes …" English mss. typescript, undated (Box 18, Folder 69)
    - Italian reprint. English translation. Typed [incomplete] and mss, 1897 (Box 18, Folder 70)
  - Eclipse: clippings, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  - Technical articles, printed, 1880, 1889 (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - Discovery of Pluto (trans-Neptunian planet) clippings, 1930 March (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - Eclipse: clippings, 1926, 1927, 1929, 1930, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 74-75)
  - Mars: pamphlets, newspaper clippings, 1877-1927, undated (Box 18, Folder 76)
  - Meteorology: printed matter, 1888, 1905, 1910, undated (Box 18, Folder 77)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings on astronomy (Box 18, Folder 78-79)
  - Aeroplanes and aeronautics correspondence, 1901-1924 (Box 19, Folder 80)
  - Aerial forts: notes, 1918 (Box 19, Folder 81)
  - Aeroplanes and aeronautics: notes, 1892-1929 (Box 19, Folder 82)
  - Photos, 1924
  - Aeroplanes and aeronautics articles by Henry Woodhouse (Box 19, Folder 83)
  - Aeroplanes and aeronautics printed matter, clippings, 1894-1929 (Box 19, Folder 84)
  - Who's Who in American Aeronautics, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 85)
  - Automatic railway builder:
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 86)
    - notes, clipping, 1902, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 87)
  - Balloon ascension experiments:
    - Correspondence, 1912-1923 (Box 19, Folder 88)
    - notes, 1910, undated (Box 19, Folder 89)
    - Negatives, glassplates, 1909, 1910 (Box 19, Folder 90)
    - Printed matter, 1910-1912 (Box 19, Folder 91)
  - Bank on wheels: notes, 1921 (Box 19, Folder 92)
  - Bells:
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 19, Folder 93)
    - Printed matter (Box 19, Folder 93-94)
  - Channel Bridge notes, drawings, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 95)
  - Chronometer: notes, 1903, 1904 (Box 20, Folder 96)
  - Copper mines in Chile correspondence, 1909-1912 (Box 20, Folder 97)
  - Copper mines, Sagasco, Chile, 1900-1912 (Box 20, Folder 98)
  - Dirigibles notes, 1915-1923 (Box 20, Folder 99)
  - Dredge:
    - Correspondence, 1918, 1927 (Box 20, Folder 100)
    - notes, 1900-1927 (Box 20, Folder 101)
    - Printed matter, 1900 (Box 20, Folder 102)
  - Elevated urban transit notes; printed matter, 1901 (Box 20, Folder 103)
  - Felt: correspondence, 1904-1905 (Box 20, Folder 104)
  - High altitude expeditions and experiments:
    - Laboratories, etc., correspondence, 1886-1889 (Box 20, Folder 105)
    - Correspondence, 1907-1912, 1915-1916 (Box 20, Folder 106)
    - Laboratories. Mt. Chimborazo, Ecuador notes, photos, 1883-1916 (Box 20, Folder 107)
    - Diagram for Meteorological Research station at Mt. Chimborazo
      See: Oversize Folio no. 1
    - Blueprints of experimental car for high altitudes: notes, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 108)
    - Printed matter (Box 20, Folder 109)
  - Interurban and Interboro Rapid Transit:
    - Correspondence, 1912-1914 (Box 21, Folder 110)
    - notes, 1899-1912 (Box 21, Folder 111)
  - Life preserver: notes, 1899-1917 (Box 21, Folder 112)
  - Nautical Strephautonome:
    - Cork, 1910-1912 (Box 21, Folder 113)
    - Copy, 1910-1912 (Box 21, Folder 114)
  - Organs: notes, printed matter, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 115)
  - Panama Canal Locks: notes, 1908-1912 (Box 21, Folder 116)
  - Planetaria: notes, printed matter, 1899, 1927 (Box 21, Folder 117)
  - Pontoons (N. River), drawings; printed matter, 1888-1901 (Box 21, Folder 118)
  - Printers' type faces:
    - Correspondence, 1911-1912 (Box 21, Folder 119)
    - notes, printed matter, 1911-1912 (Box 21, Folder 120)
  - Propellors:
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 121)
    - notes, printed matter, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 122)
  - Railroad Transport notes, printed matter, 1889-1927 (Box 21, Folder 123)
  - Roller Bearings:
    - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 21, Folder 124)
    - Printed matter, 1911-1912 (Box 21, Folder 125)
  - Salvage:
    - Correspondence, 1899-1912 (Box 22, Folder 126)
    - notes, printed matter, 1899-1909 (Box 22, Folder 127)
  - Ship Camels:
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 22, Folder 128)
    - notes and drawings, 1901 (Box 22, Folder 129)
  - Ship railway notes, drawings, printed matter, 1890-1921 (Box 22, Folder 130)
  - Ships:
    - Correspondence, 1908-1917 (Box 22, Folder 131)
    - notes, drawings, printed matter, 1890-1921 (Box 22, Folder 132)
    - Ocean transportation notes, drawings, printed matter, 1894-1918 (Box 22, Folder 133)
  - Simplified Spelling:
    - Correspondence, 1907-1912 (Box 23, Folder 134)
    - notes (Box 23, Folder 135)
    - Printed matter; press notices, 1909-1911 (Box 23, Folder 136)
  - Standard Time:
    - South America, 1907-1909 (Box 23, Folder 137)
    - notes, printed matter, 1908-1909 (Box 23, Folder 138)
  - Submarine tunnels notes, drawings, 1888, 1928 (Box 23, Folder 139)
  - Submarines notes, correspondence, 190(?)-1927 (Box 23, Folder 140)
  - Tel-electric piano player correspondence (Box 23, Folder 141)
  - Tel-electric piano player, 1901, 1910 (Box 23, Folder 142)
  - Telescopes (general), notes, clippings, printed matter, 1892-1921 (Box 24, Folder 143)
  - Telescope of 1900 Exhibition:
    - Correspondence: François Deloncle, et. al., 1908 (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - Printed matter, 1899
  - "Floating Telescope":
    - Correspondence, 1897-1902 (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - Drawing, printed matter (Box 24, Folder 146)
  - Giant telescope mounting:
    - Correspondence, 1902-1912 (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - notes, photos, clippings, 1902-1912 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - Tribune article, 1902
  - Reflecting telescope correspondence: Lyman, Josiah (Box 24, Folder 149)
  - Tides for power notes, printed matter, 1899-1916 (Box 24, Folder 150)
  - Towing device correspondence, notes, 1918 (Box 24, Folder 151)
  - Trucking correspondence notes, printed matter, 1914, 1917 (Box 24, Folder 152)
  - "Vital Engineering" correspondence included, 1927 (Box 24, Folder 153)
  - Miscaneous inventions, ideas, printed matter, 1891-1921 (Box 25, Folder 154)
  - Patent Specifications: correpondence
    - 29 May 1914-5 April 1916 (Box 25, Folder 155)
    - 22 April 1916-1 May 1916 (Box 25, Folder 156)
    - 1873-1913 (Box 25, Folder 157)
    - 1887-1908 (Box 25, Folder 158)
    - 1873-1914 (Box 25, Folder 159)
    - 1911-1914 (Box 25, Folder 160)
    - 1841-1911 (Box 25, Folder 161)
  - Eclipse of 29 July 1878, Dallas, Texas
    - Legal-personal (Box 26, Folder 162)
    - Scientific materials (Box 26, Folder 163)
    - Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 164)
    - Report by David P. Todd (Box 26, Folder 165)
    - Reports by others: Simon Newcomb, Commander W. T. Sampson, Lt. Charles G. Bowman (Box 26, Folder 166)
    - Photos and sketches made in other parts of U. S. (Box 26, Folder 167)
    - Newspaper reports on expedition (Box 26, Folder 168)
  - Transit of Venus (Box 27)
    - 4 Dec 1874, Wladiwostok:
      - Scientific and scholarly materials (Box 27, Folder 169)
      - Scientific and scholarly materials: maps and charts (Box 27, Folder 170)
    - 8 Dec 1874, Wladiwostok:
      - notes by David P. Todd (Box 27, Folder 171)
      - Report by Asaph Hall (Box 27, Folder 172)
      - Later material (Box 27, Folder 173)
    - 6 Dec 1882, Lick Observatory:
      - Scientific and scholarly materials used in preparation (Box 27, Folder 174)
      - Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 175)
      - Later correspondence (Box 27, Folder 176)
      - notes (Box 27, Folder 177)
      - notebooks no. 1 (Box 27, Folder 178)
      - notebooks no. 2, Record of photographs taken at the Lick Observatory (Box 28, Folder 179)
      - notebook: J. L. Lovell (Box 28, Folder 180)
      - Photos of astronomical phenomena (Box 28, Folder 181)
      - Photos of observatory and astronomers (Box 28, Folder 182)
      - Reports and articles by David P. Todd (Box 28, Folder 183)
    - Lick Observatory:
      - Photos, 1883 (Box 28, Folder 184)
      - 1884, 1887 (Box 29, Folder 185)
      - 6 Dec 1882, newspaper reports on expedition and Venus (Box 29, Folder 186)
      - Photos, 1884, undated (Box 29, Folder 187)
      - Lick—Venus, 1882 (Box 29, Folder 188)
      - Newspaper reports, 1882, 1883 (Box 29, Folder 189)
      - Printed matter, 1880-1959 (Box 29, Folder 190)
      - David P. Todd, "The Lick Observatory,", 1885
      - Simon Newcomb, "The Lick Observatory,", 1885
    - Venus: later newspaper materials (Box 29, Folder 191)
  - Eclipse of 19 Aug 1887, Shirakawa, Japan
    - Legal-personal: passports, etc. (Box 30, Folder 192)
    - Scientific and scholarly materials used in preparation (Box 30, Folder 193)
    - Correspondence:
      - 4 December 1886-30 June 1887 (Box 30, Folder 194)
      - 1 July-19 August 1887 (Box 30, Folder 195)
      - 20 August 1887-10 April 1889 (Box 30, Folder 196)
    - Correspondence from Simon Newcomb, 1887-1888 (Box 30, Folder 197)
    - David P. Todd scientific notes and notebooks:
      - notebook and narrative journal (Box 30, Folder 198)
      - notes (Box 31, Folder 199)
      - notebooks (Box 31, Folder 200)
      - Photographic notebook (Box 31, Folder 201)
      - notes (Box 31, Folder 202)
    - Tapes [polariscope?] (Box 31, Folder 203)
    - Tokyo clock recordings on Shirakawa chronograph 3-19 Aug 1887
    - Reports by David P. Todd (Box 31, Folder 204)
    - Reports by others: (Box 32, Folder 205)
      - W. J. Holland
      - John Pemberton
      - W. H. H. Southerland
    - One report signed by:
      - R. Kase
      - I. Agawa
      - R. Sugesawa
      - M. Katiri
    - Photos of eclipse (Box 32, Folder 206)
    - Sketches of eclipse from all parts of Japan (Box 32, Folder 207)
    - Photos of Canada; Japan (Box 32, Folder 208)
    - Photos of expedition party, Japanese astronomers, Shirakawa (Box 32, Folder 209)
    - Memorabilia, not printed (Box 32, Folder 210)
    - Printed memorabilia (Box 32, Folder 211)
    - Newspaper reports on the expedition (Box 33, Folder 212)
    - Unidentified Japanese material (Box 33, Folder 213)
    - Printed Memorabilia:
      - Booklets (Box 33, Folder 214)
      - Business and calling cards (Box 33, Folder 215)
    - Financial records (Box 33, Folder 216)
    - Collection of Japanese newspapers (Box 33, Folder 217)
  - Fuji Expedition—Boyden Fund, 1887
    - Legal—re: Boyden Fund and biography of Uriah Boyden (Box 33, Folder 218)
    - Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 219)
    - David P. Todd scientific notes (Box 33, Folder 220)
    - Report by E. Knipping (Box 33, Folder 221)
    - Financial memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 222)
    - Views of Mt. Fuji and environs (Box 33, Folder 223)
    - Box contains Japanese newspapers dealing with the Eclipse of 1887. (Box 34)
    - Proposed expedition, July 1888 (Box 35, Folder 224)
      - Rocky Mountains, B. C.
      - Atmosphere test (Boyden Fund)
  - Eclipse of 1 Jan 1889, Western U. S. (Box 35, Folder 225)
    - Instructions for Observing the Sun (Box 35, Folder 225)
    - Correspondence, 14 November-31 December 1888 (Box 35, Folder 226)
    - Reports by observers (Box 35, Folder 227)
    - Reports by telegraph; telegraphic code (Box 35, Folder 228)
    - Drawings: sun's corona, by many observers (Box 35, Folder 229)
    - Drawings of sun's corona:
      - Hon. Trenmore Coffin (Box 35, Folder 230)
      - C. N. Irish
      - Reno, Nevada
    - Composite drawing of sun's corona by Mabel Loomis Todd (Box 35, Folder 231)
    - Photos of sun's corona (Box 35, Folder 232)
    - Newspaper reports (Box 35, Folder 233)
  - Eclipse of 22 Dec 1889, Angola; Voyage of Pensacola (Box 36)
    - Legal-personal (Box 36, Folder 234)
    - Books, background material (Box 36, Folder 235)
    - Maps (Box 36, Folder 236)
    - Bulletin (Box 36, Folder 237)
    - Telegraphic codes (Box 36, Folder 238)
    - Correspondence (Box 36, Folder 239)
    - Correspondence of Capt. R. L. Pythian re: organizing expedition, 28 Mar—23 August 1889 (Box 36, Folder 240)
    - David P. Todd journal, 6 July 1889—14 May 1890 (Box 36, Folder 241)
    - notes by David P. Todd (Box 36, Folder 242)
      See: Teaching and Lecturing, lectures on Angola-Pensacola, Series IV, box 90, folder 37
      See: Writings: Unpublished Articles, St. Helena in 1890 (mss. and photographs), Series III, box 84, folder 226
    - Reports:
      - by David P. Todd (Box 37, Folder 243)
      - Unidentified (Box 37, Folder 244)
      - On cloud observations, by Cleveland Abbe (Box 37, Folder 245)
      - Linguistic, ethnological, by Heli Chatelain (Box 37, Folder 246)
      - On natural history and ethnological objects by:
        - F. W. True (Box 37, Folder 247)
        - T. H. Bean (Box 37, Folder 247)
        - Robert E. C. Stearns (Box 37, Folder 247)
        - W. H. Brown (Box 37, Folder 247)
        - James E. Benedict (Box 37, Folder 247)
        - O. Mason (Box 37, Folder 247)
      - On plants from Ascension, by Sereno Watson (Box 37, Folder 248)